It is autumn in my valley,
one of the great wonders of the Cascade
Mountains.
It is when the golden larches burst
forth in all their glory, as do the
quaking aspens,
only weeks before they shiver off their
leafy coats.
Everything exists in shades of gold,
emerald, and rust. And whenever I'm
outdoors, I exist in a state of
perpetual wonder.
[Music]
In contrast during the quickly darkening
evenings, I have often found myself
rather world-weary.
I'm often afraid to check the news to
see only more tragedy, more greed, more
fear.
And yet, there is a light in my soul
that I do wish desperately to attend and
to share with others.
And so, I'm back here not to feed your
world-weariness,
but instead to challenge it.
To challenge you to seek out wonder,
love, and beauty within the storms.
And so, here I am again to offer videos
to you.
But, and this time, things will be
different.
Since you saw me last, I have changed. I
am a mother now. I'm also older.
I'm also happier, though I often feel I
don't deserve to be.
And I also recently fulfilled the
lifelong dream of becoming the owner of
a little bookstore.
[Music]
I did it.
I can't believe it.
Well over a year ago, I started down the
path of trying to purchase my local
bookstore.
I learned a lot along the way, and it
was not until October 1st that I
actually officially became the owner.
Was it absolutely terrifying? Yes.
Extremely exciting? Also, yes.
Have I nearly gotten an ulcer from the
stress of it all? Yes. Am I happy I
persisted in this endeavor?
So far, yes.
And I can say I'm fiercely proud of who
I've become in the process.
As someone who could barely leave their
home or find a moment of mental peace 4
years ago due to having such extreme
anxiety,
I've come such a long way.
I've healed my nervous system, if only
by learning how to honor my limits and
who I am.
Though of course, I continue to relearn
lessons along the way.
Why else live?
[Music]
If I told you I simply reopened my
bookshop under new ownership on a fine
autumn day right before Hallow's Eve
with not much to do about anything, that
would be a lie.
Preparing this bookstore for reopening
was a daunting task that required a lot
of cleaning, organizing, ordering,
scheduling, managing, opening accounts,
stressing over finances, and being
slapped in the face with just how
expensive it is to survive as a
brick-and-mortar small business.
Ever a lover of stories, I think this
chapter in the life of this bookstore
has gone in a surprisingly fairy tale
sort of way
along with the trials and tribulations.
So, let me tell you the tale of
reopening Trails End Bookstore.
But, we must first travel back in time
to October 1st.
I started that morning by having a
terrible trembling in my hands and
nausea that wouldn't go away.
I was nervous. But as a highly sensitive
person, we must learn to be brave and
cope in order to be able to pursue
certain dreams.
Firstly, I decided to close down for 2
weeks in order the store and reorganize,
despite the dismal financial
implications. The main reason for this
was that my mother was visiting my
sister in the south, and I knew that to
start any endeavor, especially with a
toddler who loves his abuelita, I would
have to have her by my side.
So, we decided to open again on the 14th
when my mother would be back. Or so I
thought. This tale has some unexpected
twists and turns.
Being closed for 2 weeks gave me just
enough time, I so naively thought, to do
a mammoth amount of tasks, not limited
to repairing bookshelves, painting
tables, receiving a pile of new
inventory, preparing for the holidays,
calling up publishers, trying to get our
website up and running, getting fiber
optic internet, and also generally
learning how to manage everything.
Consequently, I spent every evening in
fervent meditation to manage my anxiety.
As you can imagine, this was impossible
to do in 13 days, and it did not take
too long before I was absolutely and
completely overwhelmed.
My perfectionism to blame.
While I have respected their privacy by
not showing them on camera, some
incredible friends and employees came
together in order to do inventory of the
entire store. It took the first whole
week. I spent much of this time trying
desperately to fill my knowledge gaps,
while also being humbled realizing that
one can only succeed with patience,
practice, and imperfection.
[Music]
I had a lot of computer work to do, but
I did take many respites from all of
that in order to have some fun
decorating.
[Music]
There are high shelves around the
entrance of the bookstore. They had
about an inch of dust on them, and a lot
of the books were actually related to
war. To me, a bookstore should be a safe
space where the terrors of the world are
kept at bay. So, I ended up placing a
lot of them spine in and getting rid of
quite a few. Unfortunately, this left me
with a lot of empty space with no books
to fill it. I wasn't sure what to do.
Initially, I was going to leave the
shelves bare, but then the next morning,
my bookish father arrived with the
perfect solution.
He decided to loan out his prized
collection of Reader's Digest until I
got the chance to collect my own set of
classics to put on display.
I have much gratitude he was willing to
share books that meant so much to him.
[Music]
These are awesome, Dad.
Yeah.
[Music]
century, baby.
You know.
Yeah.
Ooh, Around the World in 80
[Music]
and any other Western canon.
So, there's a lot of Mark Twain. Yeah.
Common oil. There's a lot of Charles
Dickens. Yeah.
In fact, I think the only non-Western
one is Tales of the Granny.
Yeah.
Goofy.
Moi bien. Moi bien. I stopped here
because those are all Sherlock Holmes
Yeah.
Which I think it's okay.
You know what this box is?
Mhm. This is the box that my Lego went
It was at this point that I was just
beginning to hope that we would be able
to reopen on the 14th.
However, that is when I got very, very
sick. I woke up feeling like I had a
terrible stomach flu. I was not fit to
work and spent nearly the entire day in
bed.
This made me pessimistic about having
the bookstore ready in time.
However, when I finally dragged myself
out of bed and drove into town, I was
greeted with something unexpected. My
mother, who was still far away visiting
my sister, had heard of my struggles and
wanted to help. So, she had hired an
amazing cleaning crew to deep clean the
entire store. Everything from wiping
down the ceiling to shampooing the
carpet.
When I walked in, bracing myself to see
clutter and dust, instead was met with
something beautiful.
My heart was all aflutter once again
with possibilities of actually opening
this store in time.
On the 13th, the day before opening, I
discovered that not only had my mother's
car broken down in Seattle, and she was
unable to be there for opening, but our
credit card reader wasn't working. At
this point, I did start to
hyperventilate a bit, but good friends
and family all assured me all would be
well, even if we had to stay closed for
a while longer.
But, I was committed to opening even
though things felt imperfect.
Financially speaking, we really did need
to open our doors. A lot of projects I
wanted to execute hadn't come to
fruition. I still had tables to paint
and genre signs to design among a
hundred other things.
But, it was at this point between panic
and hope that I found a sense of peace
and understanding.
This bookstore is a journey, a process,
a story of creating a place that feels
comforting and magical. That will not
take days, nor months. It will take
years. And that is why I wanted to make
some videos for you again, to share that
dream and that tale, along with the
highs as well as the lows.
I hope you will join me.
As I do plan to post seasonal updates on
this channel.
In short, I got the card reader working
only hours before reopening, and both my
amazing employees, husband, in-laws, and
father stepped in to help me.
It was truly a community coming together
to open Trails End Books Store. I think
one of the brightest and most unexpected
parts of the story was that a viewer, as
well as a new friend named Laura,
stopped by to help before opening. She
spent several hours helping me move
bookshelves and was so kind and
encouraging. It warmed my heart and made
me so grateful to everyone who shown
support for this new chapter of our
story.
So, while I cannot say things will stay
the same and I will make videos like I
once did, I wouldn't want to say that.
The experience of life changes us in so
many ways, and
I don't want to hide that from you. And
I want to share with you the ways that
my life has changed. And so, I hope you
come along to follow the story of this
little bookstore, and I hope you will
accept me as I am,
not as someone that is static or will
always stay the same or make videos the
same, but as someone that's ever
evolving and wants to share that with
you.
Sending all my love, and I will see you
this winter for a holiday update.
[Music]
So, we are about to open for our very
first day of business. It is currently
9:45
a.m. on October 14th.
It feels so autumnal right now. All the
trees have started to turn. There is
golden yellow everywhere, and it is
raining just a little bit. And so, I
think it's just the perfect bookish day
to cozy up with a good book and
hopefully visit the bookstore. I'm very
excited. We desperately need to open.
There are just about a thousand things
left to do. I need to create new genre
signs. I need to paint. I need to make
updates. I need to fix bookshelves. I
need to decorate more, but the most
important thing really is to be back in
business so that all those other things
can be funded, and also to take time to
do those things anyway. I felt like
there is no bookish video that is
acceptable without at least one book
recommendation. And so, in the spirit of
the autumnal season and embracing
mystery and maybe just a little bit of
spookiness, I wanted to recommend to you
The Fox Wife is one of my favorite books
I've read so far this autumn. It does
involve murder. It does involve some
dark things. The main protagonist is
hunting for someone that has done her
wrong. However, it also has a lot of
heart. It really encapsulates just a
little bit of the richness of Chinese
mythology, and it just goes into the
folklore behind the fox spirit, and it
has that essence of magical realism. I
love books where normal life and normal
people encounter magical, enchanted,
rather supernatural things. The genre of
magical realism is very close to my
heart, and this is also historical as
well. And so, I really enjoyed it. I
found it interesting, and I learned so
much about folklore in the process. I do
feel like I was transported to an old
world China, and it was a fascinating,
fascinating experience. So, the writing
as well was very beautiful, and the main
protagonist is so strong while dealing
with loss and grief and growing
throughout the process. And so, I think
that you may like this if you are okay
with some darker themes in your books.
Either way, I wanted to at least
recommend one book. I also have a
Patreon on Book Club where we are
currently reading The Undead Fox of
Deadwood Forest, which is an absolutely
perfect autumnal read that is very, very
cozy and not stressful at all. If that's
what you're more in the mood for, then I
would recommend that instead.
Well, it is time to open.
I've talked for long enough. So, let's
go do it, and hopefully we have a really
good day.
Ah!
[Music]
Yay!
Quinn, yay!
[Music]
Come on.
Bye.
[Music]
So, I may look a little bit bedraggled
right now,
but it's because the day has just ended,
and it was, as I anticipated, a little
bit busier than usual because a lot of
people were interested to just see the
bookstore since it had been closed for 2
weeks. And I'm so grateful to everyone
who stopped by. We had a good day. It
will still be months and months until we
are out of the red, but I have made
peace with that. That is a natural part
of starting a new endeavor such as this.
And hopefully we will be able to
continue surviving and soon enough,
hopefully, thriving. I'm just so excited
and exhausted and scared and hopeful. A
lot of feelings all at the same time.
More than anything else, I feel great
gratitude that I even have this
opportunity in the first place to do
this. And a lot of that has become
reality because of all your kindness.
While taking this hiatus of becoming a
new mom, I have been able to make ends
meet by posting on Patreon and having a
lovely group over there that has helped
me and encouraged me a lot through this
bookstore buying process, and it is also
where we discuss changes, decorations,
and renovations, and it is a great
little community that you are most
welcome to join if you want to support
this endeavor. However, I did want to
announce that we are accepting purchases
for our bookstore right now. We have a
little storefront. I will leave the
links down below. We are prepared to
take orders. If you wish to support a
small independent business, please
consider supporting us this autumn
season to help us get back on our feet
and thrive in the new year. If you
follow the website and you go to staff
recommendations, you can see all the
recommendations that I have made, as
well as baby Caspian has made, Luke has
made, and our wonderful staff members
have made. So, you can look there for
inspiration if you desire, but we have
just about everything available to you
if you just type in the browser section
what you're looking for, and we're so
happy to fulfill your order here in the
store, package it up, and I will be
making a handwritten postcard to you as
a huge thank you for supporting this new
chapter. Also, you can always get a
audiobook membership through a link down
below where you can support the
bookstore directly with your audiobook
purchases. Bookstores are a little bit
different from a lot of retail type
stores because books have a controlled
price, and the margins are very small,
sometimes as low as 40-something
percent. And so, it can be difficult to
survive as a bookstore, so we really do
rely on people who really want to help
support small businesses and not
monopolies. Thank you in advance for
anyone who wants to do this and help out
Trails and Books start a new chapter,
and we are very happy to be able to
offer you books and well wishes in
return. So, I just wanted to offer a
variety of different ways that you can
support our little bookshop if you are
feeling like it. However, you just being
here and sending well wishes is more
than enough. I understand that not
everyone is in a position to be able to
support a bookstore at this time. No
matter what, thank you so much for being
here. I will be posting bookstore
updates here on YouTube, and I will also
be, of course, as always keeping up my
Patreon account, so you will see more of
me here. I'm very excited to start this
new chapter, and I will see you soon to
share the bookstore during the winter
holiday season because so much will be
going on.
Sending so much love. Goodbye.
[Music]